WASIQ NASEER

MOHALI INDIA / naseerwasu23@gmail.com / +91-8527548465.

Profile.

Eight years of experience in oil, dry bulk container trade execution, order management, and sales analytics. Supplying materials in precise and timely manner to fulfil the buyer's request and carry out the execution as per contract. Experience in collecting bills, Order Management, and shipping manifests to guarantee complete adherence to international and local customs laws. Track record of identifying redundancies and maximizing resources to streamline process.

Skills.

Trade Execution Order Management Customer clearance
Service delivery Sales analytics Credit Monitoring.
Inventory Management Process Improvement Letter of credit

Data Reporting. Supply chain Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

1. Associate Team Lead Trade Operations. (Bunge India Pvt Ltd Mohali). Dec 2021 – Present.

Roles.

- Handling complete Operational service of Dry and Bulk containers from SSC office Bunge India Pvt.Ltd.
- Responsible for ensuring overseeing the execution of containers from USA, Brazil, Argentina Australia for soybeans meals, proteins, and lecithin (Food, Feed) to destinations like Vietnam, Indonesia. Philippines South Korea Thailand, Malaysia Middle east.
- Coordinating and controlling the cycle of transportation for container movements and building strong relationships with oversee distributors and partners.
- Communication with origins and destination location agents regarding shipment status for clarence.
- Deal with letter of credit, checking LC draft received from buyers end and providing comments before issuance.
- Presentation of documents against LC to Ist class Singapore banks such as Wells Fargo, commerz bank, DBS bank, Paribas bank, JP morgan & Citi bank.
- Preparing of Internal company documents such as Invoice, packing list cover letter and draft documents for presentation to bank for CAD via bank payment and for LC payments.
- Ensure Purchase, sale settlement and other vendor settlement on due dates to avoid any penality as per contractual terms.
- Maintaining all lecithin stock reports of Ex-bond warehouse including GRN, inventory report and updating
 unsold position of Inventory at warehouse to traders and warehouse managers.
- Coordinating with finance controller about the inventory stock at warehouse and accordingly creating the Insurance via Marsh Portal for inventory storage.
- Investigate and resolve Price discrepancies with full understanding of Price Structure, Margin expectations and cost within SAP price routine.
- Execution of vessels with cargo of approx..40 million in value and handling an average of 5 to 6 vessels in a month.
- Execution Of Sales, Purchase and freight, commission invoices via SAP.
- Interest calculation Calculate interest on delayed payments late shipments exceeding the shipment period and specification allowance calculation for commodities as per contractual terms.

2. Country Support Specialist (Nunhems India Pvt Ltd BASF.

July 2016 -30 Nov 2021.

Roles:

Order Management, liaising with custom agents at port for clearance, Inventory planning and Replenishment.

- Provided quality order management support in terms of order placement, order tracking, shipping
 arrangements, delivery reconciliation, invoice reconciliation, reporting and problem/situation resolution to our
 Export customers.
- Preparing & sharing demand plans for exports with the Sales Team for APAC region to assist Production department in preparing long term planning to meet the DOH target.
- Complaint coordinator for APAC (Asia pacific) region EQMS training to authorized stakeholders and coordination among different stakeholders for compliant investigation for their closure.
- Perform day to day financial transactions, including verifying, classifying, computing, posting, and recording accounts receivables' data in the system and verifying discrepancies to resolve clients billing issues.
- Rebate Management Calculation of rebate schemes for almost 20 varieties and sharing the discount to all the customers falling under the scheme criteria.

Order Management Specialist. (Nunhems India Pvt. Ltd).

Oct 2014 — June 2016

- Managed orders, renewals, order backlog, order related queries, order escalations and order alerts Utilized Salesforce to process orders and renewals, subscriptions, and professional services in a fast paced, deadline-oriented environment.
- Generated and delivered invoices, managed invoice upload into CRM resolving any processing/billing issues.
- Adhered to all compliance guidelines and supported internal and external audits Interfaced with Global Services
 Contract Coordinators, Order Administration, and Contracts Renewal as well as customers both internal and
 external to provide accurate contract information.
- Creating Credit and Debit Notes for customers at the year end.
- Salesforce- training to sales and new Joinee for excess of sales force and placing the orders, creating prospects, preparing business plan, Monitoring the field visits.
- Extraction of weekly complaints by potential customers posted on Salesforce tool and discussion with Sales managers for the solutions and way forward to avoid such complaints in future.
- Maintaining the Master data of all the 1500 customers in salesforce.

Education:

- Diploma in Supply chain management and logistics (2021-2022- Michigan University).
- Master of Business Administration from Punjab Technical University (2012 2014).